BRYAN HENSON

www.bryandavidhenson.com

Career Profile

Multi-disciplinary designer and military veteran focused on user interaction, communication, and development with 10 years of industry experience and an upcoming December 2018 graduate from the University of Texas at Arlington, Bachelor of Arts in Communication Technology. Successfully developed and managed multimedia production, curriculum and course development, and mentored junior leadership to the highest military standard.

Able to clearly instruct and develop course curriculum to all knowledge levels in communication technology, development, and design. Empathetic and selfless designer willing to learn new knowledge sets and deliver intelligent, refined results. Seasoned leader and experienced manager in an agile, fast-paced delivery cycle.

Career Highlights

- Chosen as UTA Communication Technology's ambassador to meet with distinguished keynote speaker at Communication Day 2017
- Distinguished Honor Graduate and peer-chosen leadership award U.S. Army Advanced Leader Course
- Hand-chosen by top-tier Special Forces Commander as the dedicated Commander's Photographer
- Recognized by U.S. Army as one of the top photographers in the 2015 Best in Photos Feature

Professional Experience

Bryan Henson Design

Arlington, TX September 2014 - Present

7th Special Forces Group (Airborne)

Eglin AFB, FL July 2013 - August 2016

6th Military Information Support Battalion (Airborne)

USASOC Fort Bragg, NC December 2008 - July 2013

Freelance Designer

- Provide content strategy and design consultations; manage branding identity and social marketing for 5 local businesses
- Worked with Wet-N-Wild Toronto for digital motion advertisement, 2% Click-Through Rate
- Design logos, print collateral, and signage for distribution

U.S. Army Staff Sergeant | Lead Graphic Designer | Photographer

- Lead designer of over 12,000 multimedia products in support of a 2,500 Soldier unit
- Selected as the Commander's Photographer for two years; provided coverage for over 200 Special Forces training missions, events, VIP and government official visits
- Developed and taught curriculum based programs of instruction in graphic design, photography, and multimedia to 30 Soldiers and civilians - increased tested competency by 30%
- Directed logo creation, print collateral, video motion graphics, and signage for distribution

U.S. Army Sergeant | Graphic Designer | Photographer

- Directed the style, design and technical requirements for missions in Djibouti, Africa and at Fort Bragg, NC to storyboard and develop visual information multimedia products
- Developed and taught curriculum based programs of instruction in graphic design and multimedia to 20 Soldiers - increased tested competency 20%
- Responsible for designing and producing multimedia products on multiple platforms for diverse audiences, including Department of Defense officials and senior U.S. and foreign government representatives

Education

University of Texas at Arlington

Arlington, TX

Projected Graduation: December 2018

U.S. Army NCO Academy Fort Meade, MD

201

Defense Information School

Fort Meade, MD 2011

Bachelor of Arts in Communication Technology

Design and utilize the latest communication technology for the modern web, such as responsive/mobile-first web design, interface design, interactive multimedia creation, user experience, and web development.

Advanced Leader Course

Distinguished Honor Graduate, Multimedia Award, Peer-selected for Leadership Award. Ranked 1st out of graduates.

Digital Multimedia Course

Provides intermediate training in the knowledge and skills needed to create and integrate text, graphics, sound, animation and full-motion video into multimedia and web-based packages. Ranked 2nd out of graduates.

Volunteer Activities

Corey Academy of Fine Arts

Arlington, TX 2018

Volunteer member of Watch DOGS (Dad's of Great Students)

Provide positive male role model for students, demonstrative by presence that education and safety is important. Provide an extra set of eyes/ears to enhance school security and reduce bullying.